There, that must be it.
Wow, it looks like Sora's
family runs a barbershop.
Excuse me!
Oh for Pete's sake...
Sorry, but the shop is
already closed for today.
G-good evening.
Who might you be, missy?
Um...
I'm... here to make a delivery.
Where to go? The land, sea or sky?
Ahiru no Sora
I wanna invite you to come along
The pages of our story have started to turn
If you lose your nerve then recycle it
And let it push you past hesitation
Give and go! With the flow
Instincts that are buried deep
will always rear their head again
People can't just hide the
dreams they once dreamed of
Even if these wings can't fly
We want to spread them
wide and embrace the sky
Becoming the people who we want to be
You never know, the impossible
could be possible tomorrow
So let's keep up the struggle
Happy go ducky!
I do apologize for the trouble.
The Troublesome Freshman
This boy's such a heavy sleeper,
nothing ever wakes him up.
Playing himself to sleep... I swear,
he must have basketballs for brains.
Um, ma'am...
You've got his feet poking
out where his head should be.
Oh, it's fine, it makes no
big difference either way.
Anyway missy, your bangs seem
like they could use a little touch up.
Huh?
Since you brought my grandson home,
I'll give you a quick trim.
Go sit down.
Um, but I...
Enough fussin'.
You're quite the lucky girl,
I only do cuts when I'm in a good mood.
They used to say I was a prodigy
blessed by the gods, ya know.
Your hands are shaking! Are
you really sure about this?!
You've got some really
beautiful black hair, missy.
Don't ever go dying it now, ya hear?
Something the matter?
That picture.
Is she possibly...?
Oh, that's just my daughter.
She's also Sora's mother.
Though she's dealing with a
bit of an illness right now.
She's in one of those big,
fancy government hospitals.
Is it a very serious illness?
Huh?
Uh, well, Sora mentioned to me before
that he couldn't see his mother right now.
It's not that he can't.
It's that she won't.
Huh?
That boy used to live deep in the countryside
of the Nagano Prefecture.
It was really out in the middle of nowhere.
A hospital in Kanagawa?
Yes. She'll be moving there
for treatment starting next month.
Is her illness going to get
better if she goes there?
Of course. The facilities there
are much better than ours,
and they have many incredibly
skilled doctors on staff.
Oh really? Then I guess we'll
be separated for a while.
Yes, you will.
Okay then, how about this?
I'll apply for a school in Kanagawa!
If I get into a school that's
close to where the hospital is,
then I can come see you whenever!
It's best to have someone by your side
in case there's ever trouble!
Right?
No.
Huh?
But why?
I'm not going there for fun.
I'm going to that hospital
to battle my condition.
And I won't be the only one.
The doctors and nurses there will also
be helping me to keep fighting against it.
Letting kids like you hang out there all the time,
will only cause trouble for them.
That's why I don't need you to come, Sora.
Are... you serious?
You think I'm a problem just being there?
Do you... not even want
me to be around, mom?!
Hey, listen Sora.
Your mother just-
Forget it.
Sora?
Sora! What do you think you're doing?!
Then just go off to Kanagawa
or wherever the hell you want!
Even if you beg me...
...I'm never going to come to visit you!
Wait! Sora!
I can't believe him.
You know, you're both two peas in a pod.
You're both... really bad at lying.
If Sora actually came with
me all the way to Kanagawa,
I know he would spend every minute he could
at the hospital, both after
school and on the weekends.
And that would mean
he couldn't practice basketball at all...
I know.
You don't have to say another word.
I'm so sorry.
I just don't want to become
a burden in Sora's life.
Okay then, take care of
everything while I'm away.
Don't worry about us.
We're going to be just fine,
so you stay focused on getting better.
Great. Thank you.
Last chance, Sora. Your mom's about to leave.
Bye for now, Sora.
Try to stop being such a picky eater
and learn to clean your plate.
And don't forget, you're
finishing middle school soon.
You can't just play basketball all the time,
you have to study hard for your entrance exams.
And also-
When I get to high school...!
When I get to high school,
I'll join the basketball team right away!
I'll become a way better player than I am now,
and grow way taller!
I'll get on the team's starting lineup!
Then I'll make sure that we
win our first big tournament!
And after all that...!
And after all that... when I'm the very best,
with a perfect record...
Then can I... take our winning trophy...
and come to visit you?
Yeah! I'll be waiting!
I've never heard him be so cocky before.
The first tournament that'll
be held in high school...
...is the national inter-high.
We'll never see each other again. Dummy.
After that, he took the entrance exams
for schools out here.
And eventually came stumbling into my house.
His dad thought this would
be the best thing for him.
Even though his mom told
him not to come here?
Yeah.
He's keeping it all a big secret from her.
So that he can go visit her the instant
he wins that tournament.
I see.
Though I already let it slip
the last time I saw her.
That ruins the surprise!
They really do love each other so much.
That day, when I told her about it...
...she had the happiest
look that I've ever seen.
He's awake.
Wait a second, Sora.
Where are you going?
To school.
I still haven't done my
1,000 shots for today.
N-no way...
Oh, hey.
What are you doing at our place, Madoka?
Huh?
He doesn't remember anything?
What a crazy coincidence!
This is actually where I live!
So, uh, does this mean... that match
didn't wear you out enough to skip practice?
I somehow slept a whole
bunch, so I think I'm okay.
That's because you were sleeping
the whole time while I carried you here...
But you know, it's already pretty late.
You should just put it off.
No, I can't.
I can deal with losing a practice match,
but I absolutely cannot lose at the inter-high.
I have to practice as much as possible.
Sora...
That's right.
You need to hurry and see your mother again.
Okay, you're all done.
Oh, great.
Thanks a lo-
That'll be 1,500 yen.
Huh?
For the cut. 1,500 yen.
Oh wait, did I say this was a favor?
Fine, I'll settle for 1,490 yen.
Pay up.
Okay.
But wait...
...now my bangs are way too short.
I guess I should probably
get some sleep soon.
I ended up staying up
all night playing games.
But whatever.
Today is Sunday, anyway.
Is that one of the elementary kids?
I'm super impressed that they would
get up this early just to practice dribbling.
It's great to see such passion in the youth,
things are looking bright for the future of Japan.
Stop the presses. I know that spikey head.
Oh jeez, I can't believe him!
It's Sunday for Heaven's sake!
Not to mention, it's 5:00 in the morning!
And he just collapsed from
exhaustion yesterday!
While I'm at it...
He's already made it that far? So quick!
But wait, just how far is he planning to run?
That's the Nikotama line...
Then we've come as far as Setagaya...
Oh come on, you can run more than that!
I'm so done with this! I swear I'm never
giving piggyback rides ever again!
I had never really noticed this
until Tokiwa pointed it out to me.
But it's obvious that I score significantly fewer shots
when I take them from the left side.
Actually, that's not my only problem.
His defense was so solid
that I couldn't do anything to get around it.
I have to perfect my drive.
Make it faster! Make it smoother!
If I can shake off the defense,
then my odds of scoring will definitely improve!
My two-handed shot still
needs some work, but...
...if I can work out the kinks, then I can use it
to overcome my weakness on the left side!
I want more skills.
I want to get even better!
HEY!
I'm sorry!
Uh, M-Madoka...?
What are you doing here?
Even the best players in the world, don't go hard
on practice the day after they play a game.
If you keep practicing like this,
you're going to put yourself in the hospital someday.
Madoka's in her casual clothes.
It's kind of exhilarating to see.
Are you listening to me?
I'm listening! I swear!
Well shoot, it looks like somebody
already beat us to the punch.
It's Nabe and Chuckie!
And Yasuhara is with them, too!
Can you believe it?
Yasu was so bummed about his ejection
yesterday that he was like,
"let's go do some secret training!"
Don't put words in my mouth, dude!
I just figured we could kill time
playing some basketball, that's all.
Great! Then let's all practice together!
Oh jeez, give me a break already!
If you want to practice, then you can just
run yourselves ragged doing it tomorrow!
Huh?
We're not allowed to practice?
Yep. You can't.
Use of the court for practice is on a rotation
between the girls' basketball team,
the badminton team, and
also the volleyball team.
Hold up, what about us then?!
We had no problem using
it for practice last week!
That's only because you came here before anyone else
and laid claim to the court, right?
No one had the nerve to say anything.
They were too scared of you.
Then, how about you just
put us into that rotation?
That's not an option.
If you would like to participate
as an official school team,
then you'll need to find a proper advisor
and also get permission from the principal.
Until you do that, you have no right
to be doing any sort of activities on this court.
Are you picking a fight, old man?!
Stop it, Yasu.
Um... so it's okay as long as we
don't use the court, right?
Huh?
Well, I get that this isn't
technically the court but...
Hey Nabe, keep your eyes straight ahead!
Dude, I can't stand to look!
Momoharu said he would talk the principal
into getting us an advisor, so hopefully...
That's assuming it all goes well.
BOYS'
BASKETBALL
TEAM
Yo! Welcome back, little bro.
The hell are you doing in here, man?
Isn't it cool? I found it lying around
behind the supermarket.
I paid the principal a visit.
Oh yeah? How'd it go?
He agreed to set us up with an advisor.
But only on one condition.
If we get into any fights, or cause any
other sort of problem, the team
gets disbanded immediately.
I'll give it about a week, then.
We'll see.
Chiaki, be straight with me.
Are you serious about basketball? For real?
Hard to say.
After having my passion for
the game killed back then,
I'm not sure it will ever come back.
Don't pretend it's not your fault.
You might have been the only
one running on the court.
But you're still the one who up
and left the game at halftime.
That's true.
But I'm nearly there, all I
need is a little incentive...
...then I think I could reignite my passion.
I'm so close.
Just one thing!
Chiaki...
S'cuse me!
We are, like, totally hoping to be managers
for the basketball team!
Passion reignited. Let's do this.
We were stuck on the stage
for the entire practice session.
There's not much we can do.
We're still too new at this
to be practicing how to shoot, anyway.
We're not going to make much progress
by practicing basketball without a basket, though.
Holy shit!
Even a newbie like me can tell...
...this guy is probably an expert!
H-he's giving me goosebumps!
Yo!
Huh?
You've got really sick basketball skills.
Is this ball yours? It's really worn out.
How'd you do that move?
Could you show us again?
We're members of the basketball team.
But to be honest, we hardly even know
how to dribble the ball.
From what I just saw, you dribble like a pro.
It was almost as if the ball
was glued to your hand or something.
So, do us a favor and show
us those sick moves again.
The gym isn't the only place with a basket!
I can practice shooting if I do it over here!
Yasuhara!
What the hell do you think
you're doing, punk?!
I'm no "punk."
The name's Kite.
Do I need to teach you a lesson
in proper manners? Well, senpai?
I think this punk has a few screws loose.
All right, then.
Let's see what you can teach
after I pound your face in!
Chuckie!
You're too slow. This
won't even be a challenge.
Cocky bastard! I'll knock you down a peg!
Who even... is this guy?
What're you lookin' at, shrimp?
You want a lesson, too?
I doubt you could even put up a fight.
It'd be like me crushing an ant.
Don't take me so lightly.
You crossed the line.
CALCIUM BAR
And I'm gonna make you pay for it!
As a 100th degree black belt in karate,
I'll pound you into the dirt!
Quit your bullshit!
Why attack me, Yasuhara?
You just stay out of this!
That surprise attack was a cheap move, man.
Just so you know, I'm a legit
2nd degree black belt in karate.
But I'm a little clumsy, so I'm not good
at pulling my punches. Sorry in advance.
Okay. Bring it on.
That's enough!
Momoharu!
Don't lay a hand on him, Yasu.
Why the hell not?!
I'll explain things later.
Just bear with it.
This doesn't bode well for
the future at all, dammit.
Sorry man, we can't afford
to be getting into any fights right now.
So let's all just call
it quits for today. Deal?
Wait a damn minute.
You can't just expect to
turn tail and run from me.
I don't give a shit about your problems.
What are you trying to get at?
I can tell from the look in your eyes.
You're the boss of this group.
Greased
Lightning
So fight me.
He's got tattoos!
Whatever the case,
I've already decided to retire from fighting.
I've got more important things to do
than waste time dealing with idiots like-
So fast!
You're just as slow as them.
Momoharu!
Did he seriously just counter
that kick with a headbutt?!
Don't make me have to repeat myself, dammit.
I can't fight you right now.
Are you a member of the
basketball team like them?
Yep.
That's just wonderful.
Now I've got something to look forward to.
Wh-what exactly happened between you guys?
Hell if I know. He just came swinging at me
out of nowhere.
Is something wrong, Momoharu?
Take a good look.
Do you see the last spot
that he was standing in?
He was almost all the way back to where
the three-point line would be.
And what about it?
You didn't notice?
In the blink of an eye
that jerk managed to...
...fly all the way to where I
was with just a single bound.
He must never skip leg day
with explosive power like that...
BOYS'
BASKETBALL
TEAM
So we get disbanded if we
cause any trouble at all?
I see, that explains your attitude yesterday.
Yep. Fights are out of the question.
I asked around my class for some
info and found out that guy
had been suspended up until yesterday.
He's totally bad news.
But, you know, he was still
really good at basketball.
I know it's time for practice,
but aren't we stuck on the stage again?
Playing without a basket really sucks.
I must be going crazy or something.
I actually want to see how well
that punk from yesterday can play.
What's this?
What's the matter?
Did something happen?
Outta my way, losers!
That dumbass!
Shit! Somebody stop him!
Stop! Stop!
We aren't allowed to use the court right n-
Huh?
Look out!
Now he's done it!
Are you all right, Yoshino?!
Wait! We shouldn't move her around!
Hang in there, Yoshino!
Yoshino?
Shit. This is a disaster.
It didn't matter how long
you stared up at the sky
You always said that you
would never be able to fly
One night I cried wondering
how long it would take
Until I could finally reach you with my hands
Eventually I got used to just running away
Until the day I realized that was a weakness
So let's start it all over, right now
The things precious to us
were always close at hand
We are never completely alone
at any time in our lives
The truth is that you can
fly, wherever you want
Spreading your wings to go
far higher than anyone else
The more tears that you shed
Then the stronger you become
Let's use those wings
to travel the world over
And find a path to a future
that no one knows about
Always, always, always
Walking onwards, all of us together
Ahiru no Sora
Next Time: The Duck
and the Kite
Next time: "The Duck and the Kite."